<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>terraform on SpareSlant Technical Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/terraform/</link>
    <description>Recent content in terraform on SpareSlant Technical Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/terraform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>(Version-2) Multiple Stacks TerraformCDK Python Oracle Cloud Infrastructure (OCI)</title>
      <link>/posts/v2-multiple-stacks-terraformcdk-python-oci/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/v2-multiple-stacks-terraformcdk-python-oci/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Terraform has released a new version of cdktf = 0.9.0. This version makes cross referencing across stacks easy. This document will explore this feature. It is built upon previous version of code mentioned below.
 previous version of code  https://github.com/spareslant/oci_multi_stack_terraform_cdk_python We will be creating a public facing VM in Oracle Cloud Infrastructure (OCI) using terraform cdk toolkit. We will be writing terraform code in Python and we will be using terraform stacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Stacks TerraformCDK Python Oracle Cloud Infrastructure (OCI)</title>
      <link>/posts/multiple-stacks-terraformcdk-python-oci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 13:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/multiple-stacks-terraformcdk-python-oci/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We will be creating a public facing VM in Oracle Cloud Infrastructure (OCI) using terraform cdk toolkit. We will be writing terraform code in Python and we will be using terraform stacks.
What will be done in terraform stack  We will create a stack priv_user_compartment to create a privileged user cdk-user and a compartment CDK. This user will have full admin rights in this compartment. We will create a stack network to create VCN, subnets, internet gateway, dhcp options, route tables etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform CDK Create OCI OracleCloudInfraStructure VM</title>
      <link>/posts/terraform-cdk-create-oci-oraclecloudinfrastructure-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 23:40:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/terraform-cdk-create-oci-oraclecloudinfrastructure-vm/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We will be using terraform-cdk toolkit in this article. We shall be using an OCI (Oracle Cloud Infrastructure) account to spin up a VM.
We shall be doing following.
Manual steps to prepare cloud environment first (using oci-cli)  Create a new user account cdk-user (apart from the tenancy admin) and new compartment called as CDK for this user. cdk-user will have full privleges to CDK compartment. This is done as per Oracle recommended practices for OCI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform Cdk</title>
      <link>/posts/terraform-cdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 17:54:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/terraform-cdk/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We will be exploring the terraform-cdk toolkit in this article. We shall be using an AWS account to spin up a VM. We shall be doing following.
 Create A brand New VPC (Not touching existing default VPC) Create 3 subnets ( 1 public, 2 private) A security Group to allow incoming SSH traffic and allow all outgoing. A key-pair for ssh An additional internet-gateway in AWS (It is needed to get internet connectity to new VPC.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
